<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Pushkar Ghanekar</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Pushkar Ghanekar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 18:56:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian Deployment Triggers</title>
      <link>/projects/copyofcontributions/deploy-triggers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/copyofcontributions/deploy-triggers/</guid>
      <description>Addressed pretty significant page load performance issue founde in larger deployments. Eliminates uses of intensive backend query, replacing it with an asynchronous API call against a lucene index. This change reduces page load from from 2+ minutes to nearly instant, with an incredibly responsive UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catalysis at Metal/Oxide Interfaces: Water Gas Shift at Pt/MgO Boundaries</title>
      <link>/publications/ptmgo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/ptmgo/</guid>
      <description>Synopsis: Catalysts comprising of metal nanoparticles dispersed on oxide supports have found applications in a vast number of chemical processes related to energy generation and environmental. In some cases, the interface between the metal and the supporting oxide is theorized to exhibit unique reactivity compared to just the metal or the oxide in isolation.
Water-Gas Shift reaction (WGSR) is one such reaction which is expected to show sensitivity to such metal/oxide interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electronic and Structural modification of Pt-V alloy and its consequences for Propane Dehydrogenation Catalysis</title>
      <link>/publications/pt3v/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/pt3v/</guid>
      <description>Synopsis: Combination of experimental kinetics, state-of-the-art characterisation techiques and computation catalyst models to investigate the active site for propane dehydrogenation reaction. It is shown that alloying noble metals, platinum in this case, with another element (like vanadium) leads to changes in the catalytic performance. Through combined experiment/theory effort these performance and stability changes can be explained by perturbation in the electronic and structural properties of the alloys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organically DevOps: Building Quality and Security into the Software Supply Chain at Liberty Mutual</title>
      <link>/blog/alldaydevops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/alldaydevops/</guid>
      <description>This talk looked at Liberty Mutual’s transformation to Continuous Integration, Continuous Delivery, and DevOps. For a large, heavily regulated industry, this task can not only be daunting, but viewed by many as impossible. Often, organizations try to reduce the friction through micro-fixes, but Eddie’s team asked how to change the culture to reduce the friction and concluded with the following final points:
 Don’t mandate DevOps. Give employees the chance to master their discipline with examples to set and follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful Links</title>
      <link>/blog/beautiful_links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/beautiful_links/</guid>
      <description>YouTubers Vsauce</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Added Docker Build Status Badge to shields.io</title>
      <link>/projects/copyofcontributions/shields-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 17:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/copyofcontributions/shields-docker/</guid>
      <description>Shields.io is a massive library of badges that can be inserted into project README&amp;rsquo;s or websites displaying various statuses (code coverage, health, version, etc). Support for docker was missing the current build health, and was a pretty trivial addition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schema.org Structured Data documentation fixes</title>
      <link>/projects/copyofcontributions/schema-org/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 17:08:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/copyofcontributions/schema-org/</guid>
      <description>While adding Structured Data to a client&amp;rsquo;s website I found some example JSON that was invalid. Simple contribution to cleanup the user documentation providing syntactically valid JSON documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BOSH release for Bamboo &amp; Remote Agents</title>
      <link>/projects/copyofcreations/bosh-agents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/copyofcreations/bosh-agents/</guid>
      <description>BOSH (Bosh Outer SHell) &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;is an open source tool for release engineering, deployment, lifecycle management, and monitoring of distributed systems.&amp;rdquo; And it&amp;rsquo;s amazingly powerful. This examples uses BOSH to provision an Alassian vendor app running on JDK along with the support Postgres database and agents to support it. The releases manages the health of services and will automatically provision, start/stop processes across the various services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forcing Visits to use SSL</title>
      <link>/blog/force-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/force-ssl/</guid>
      <description>Intro Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether it&amp;rsquo;s a CakePHP app for a client, your own personal CMS, or any other web based application. If your passing around passwords or other sensitive info you should really implement SSL. SSL provides 2 main perks to your visitors.
 First it encrypts all communication that flies across the web. This prevents curious or devious billies from getting your secrets. Secondly it ensures to the user that your server is in fact who it claims, and not a nasty &amp;lsquo;man in the middle&amp;rdquo; attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian Marketplace Plugins</title>
      <link>/projects/copyofcreations/marketplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/copyofcreations/marketplace/</guid>
      <description>Multiple plugins used by thousands of teams that provide enhanced functionality of Atlassian’s core products (primarily JIRA and Bamboo) to enrich CI/CD capabilities, DevOps automation, or productivity. Functionality spans user interface, web services and persistence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian optimization using Gaussian Processes</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/bo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/bo/</guid>
      <description> Notebook explaining the idea behind bayesian optimization alongside a small example showing its use. This notebook was adapted from Martin Krasser&amp;rsquo;s blogpost Good introductory write-up on Bayesian optimization here Nice lecture explaining the working of Gaussian Processes here  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker image for Bitbucket CI/CD Pipelines  &#34;shipit&#34;</title>
      <link>/projects/copyofcreations/docker-marketplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/copyofcreations/docker-marketplace/</guid>
      <description>Provides required dependencies and additional utilities to simplify and codify the process of building, testing and delivering Atlassian plugins all the way to the live marketplace.Executes integration/AUT level tests against all stated compatible versions for the productUploads generated artifact to Atlassian marketplaceProvides corresponding metadata indicating version, release notes, and compatibility</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-to-end Machine Learning Project</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/end2end_ml_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/end2end_ml_project/</guid>
      <description>This project is obtained from Aurelien Geron&amp;rsquo;s Hands-on Machine Leanring with Scikit-learn and Tensorflow (github link). The aim to predict median house values in Californian districts, given a number of features from these districts.
Main steps we will go through:
 Formulate the problem Get the data Discover and visualize data / Data exploration to gain insight Prep data for ML algorithm testing Select model and train it Fine-tuning the model  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High throughput perovskite screening</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/perovskites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/perovskites/</guid>
      <description>High throughput screening of MaterialsProject dataset using pymatgen API for estimating perovskite bulk stability. For selected candidates, analyze their surface morphology using ab-initio thermodynamic analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyTorch CNN example</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/pytorch_cnn_example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/pytorch_cnn_example/</guid>
      <description>Convolutional neural network is used to train on the CIFAR-10 dataset using PyTorch.
What does it consists of? The CIFAR-10 dataset consists of 60000 32x32 colour images in 10 classes, with 6000 images per class. There are 50000 training images and 10000 test images.
The dataset is divided into five training batches and one test batch, each with 10000 images. The test batch contains exactly 1000 randomly-selected images from each class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/search/</guid>
      <description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml
[outputs] home = [&amp;#34;HTML&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;JSON&amp;#34;] Searching additional fileds To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support Vector Machines example</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/svm_usecase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/svm_usecase/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial is adapted from Jake VanderPlas&amp;rsquo;s example of SVM as given in his reference book: Python Data Science Handbook</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web scraping IMDB Bollywood data</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/imdb_scrapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/imdb_scrapping/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web scraping S&amp;P 500 data</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/sp500/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/sp500/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>