<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Pushkar Ghanekar</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Pushkar Ghanekar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 18:56:13 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Promoting a Safe Laboratory Environment Using the Reactive Hazard Evaluation and Analysis Compilation Tools</title>
      <link>/publications/rheact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/rheact/</guid>
      <description>Synopsis: In the past several years, the U.S. Chemical Safety Board has found an increase in the frequency of laboratory accidents and injuries. A framework to document, assess, and mitigate hazards is a critical starting point for ensuring safe laboratory practices. To address this requirement, I was part of a team working on developing Reactive Hazards Evaluation Analysis and Compilation Tool (RHEACT), an online platform to compile and scrutinize hazards-related information, was developed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catalysis at Metal/Oxide Interfaces: Water Gas Shift at Pt/MgO Boundaries</title>
      <link>/publications/ptmgo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/ptmgo/</guid>
      <description>Synopsis: Catalysts comprising of metal nanoparticles dispersed on oxide supports have found applications in a vast number of chemical processes related to energy generation and environmental. In some cases, the interface between the metal and the supporting oxide is theorized to exhibit unique reactivity compared to just the metal or the oxide in isolation.
Water-Gas Shift reaction (WGSR) is one such reaction which is expected to show sensitivity to such metal/oxide interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electronic and Structural modification of Pt-V alloy and its consequences for Propane Dehydrogenation Catalysis</title>
      <link>/publications/pt3v/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/pt3v/</guid>
      <description>Synopsis: Combination of experimental kinetics, state-of-the-art characterisation techiques and computation catalyst models to investigate the active site for propane dehydrogenation reaction. It is shown that alloying noble metals, platinum in this case, with another element (like vanadium) leads to changes in the catalytic performance. Through combined experiment/theory effort these performance and stability changes can be explained by perturbation in the electronic and structural properties of the alloys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting back on my Ph.D. journey</title>
      <link>/blog/phd_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/phd_learning/</guid>
      <description>This essay is a reflection on my Ph.D. journey. I look at the few reasons I thought of pursuing it, learning from the journey, and some tips that might be helpful for someone planning to embark on a similar journey. It goes without saying that everyone&amp;rsquo;s Ph.D. experience is different and this essay reflects the learnings and opinions I have formed through my years in it.
Expectations going into a Ph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transition words and phrases markdown</title>
      <link>/blog/transitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/transitions/</guid>
      <description>Transition words/phrases are writing devices which help bridge ideas and guide the reader through the prose. When used strategically and sparingly they connect multiple ideas and make the flow you&amp;rsquo;d have planned much more clearer to the reader.
In my experience, I have made use of transition words even when delivering talks. They help add in necessary connections as you might glide through your slide deck and the information in the previous slide is not directly available to your audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/search/</guid>
      <description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml
[outputs] home = [&amp;#34;HTML&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;JSON&amp;#34;] Searching additional fileds To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
