<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Pushkar Ghanekar</title>
    <link>/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Pushkar Ghanekar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis on Spice Use in Indian Food</title>
      <link>/blog/indian_spices_network_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/indian_spices_network_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Indian food, like most of the food from the tropical region, uses a variety of different spices. Historically, the spices are thought to have been a way to increase the shelf-life and keep pests away. Anyways, if you are planning to cook more Indian food lately, it would be great to know which spices would give you most bang for your buck. More so, which spices are often used together? What is the relation between each of them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bollywood Movie Rating Analysis</title>
      <link>/blog/imdb_scrapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/imdb_scrapping/</guid>
      <description>Key results: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web scraping S&amp;P 500 data</title>
      <link>/blog/sp500/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/sp500/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Optimization using Gaussian Processes</title>
      <link>/blog/bo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/bo/</guid>
      <description> Notebook explaining the idea behind bayesian optimization alongside a small example showing its use. This notebook was adapted from Martin Krasser&amp;rsquo;s blogpost Good introductory write-up on Bayesian optimization here Nice lecture explaining the working of Gaussian Processes here  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property Price Prediction ML-model</title>
      <link>/blog/end2end_ml_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/end2end_ml_project/</guid>
      <description>This project is adapted from Aurelien Geron&amp;rsquo;s Hands-on Machine Learning Book (github link). We build a regression model to predict median house values in Californian districts, given a number of features from these districts. More importantly, this project go through the basic building blocks when setting up any ML projects.
Following are main steps to consider:
 Formulating the problem, defining the boundary conditions Data acquisition Discover and visualize data / Data exploration to gain insight Prepare data for ML algorithm training and testing Explore various model architectures to use Select model and train it Fine-tuning the model  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement CNN in PyTorch</title>
      <link>/blog/pytorch_cnn_example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/pytorch_cnn_example/</guid>
      <description>Convolutional neural network is used to train on the CIFAR-10 dataset using PyTorch.
What does it consists of? The CIFAR-10 dataset consists of 60000 32x32 colour images in 10 classes, with 6000 images per class. There are 50000 training images and 10000 test images.
The dataset is divided into five training batches and one test batch, each with 10000 images. The test batch contains exactly 1000 randomly-selected images from each class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Support Vector Machines</title>
      <link>/blog/svm_usecase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/svm_usecase/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial is adapted from Jake VanderPlas&amp;rsquo;s example of SVM as given in his reference book: Python Data Science Handbook</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perovskite Stability Analysis</title>
      <link>/blog/perovskites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/perovskites/</guid>
      <description>High throughput screening of MaterialsProject dataset using pymatgen API for estimating perovskite bulk stability. For selected candidates, analyze their surface morphology using ab-initio thermodynamic analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>